so being black in academia has many
positive and negatives whether you want
to fit in whether you want to hide
really somewhat out of place it changes
narrative I think in the case of being a
black male it's often that narrative a
kind of gang affiliated crime drugs all
those types of things it told people it
shows people by virtually being there
that I'm not a stereotype there are
negatives where you're asked to speak
for black people it's a responsibility
in the classroom to make sure that we
put our perspectives across we don't all
have to be bright musicians or something
to music or sport being black academia
to me as a political statement you can
see other people that look like you
change and shape the narrative said
about us that precede us it means more
PhDs that are black the ability to try
and inspire other people to attain a
higher level education it means more
professors that are black you have a
unique perspective you're always whether
you like it or not might as well own it
and be proud
[Music]